<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Contacts on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/contact/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Contacts on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:10:25 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/contact/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact Us</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/contact/careers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:10:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/contact/careers/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;
TotalSim LLC
555 Metro Pl N
Suite 175
Dublin, OH 43017
Phone: +1.614.255.7426
Email: 

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:totalsim.us*jobs?subject=application&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
totalsim.us||jobs
&lt;/a&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;careers:6035441c68e33538441e623a4322ab2f&#34;&gt;Careers&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TotalSim is always on the look-out for enthusiast and committed individuals to join our growing team in Dublin, Ohio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a small and almost entirely employee owned company, we do not hire very frequently but will consider resumes or CV&amp;rsquo;s of interested individuals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Candidates best suited to join TotalSim would be Mechanical and Aerospace Engineering graduates with strong analytical skills. They would be detail conscious, and work methodically in compressed timescales and to rigid deadlines. Likely positions will involve all aspects of CFD based aerodynamic development, from generation of complex models to analysis of results, and shaping the direction of design for our automotive and motorsports customers. We require US citizenship or permanent residency prior to consideration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contact us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently Available Positions&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-cfd-engineer:6035441c68e33538441e623a4322ab2f&#34;&gt;1. CFD Engineer&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CFD Engineer positions based in our Dublin Offices, providing CFD consultancy services for a wide variety of industrial applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicants for this positions will have strong analytic skills, be detail conscious, and work methodically in compressed timescales and to rigid deadlines. The positions will involve all aspects of CFD aerodynamic development, from generation of complex models to analysis of results, shaping the direction of design for our automotive and motorsports customers. Knowledge of ANSA and OpenFOAM desirable. US citizenship or permanent residency required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All applicants should be educated to Bachelors Degree level in Aeronautical or Mechanical Engineering (or equivalent).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ve hired many of our employee right out of University, but also are interested in speaking with engineers with more industry experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send resume to 

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:totalsim.us*jobs?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
totalsim.us||jobs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-client-side-web-application-intern:6035441c68e33538441e623a4322ab2f&#34;&gt;2. Client Side Web Application Intern&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Internship positions based in our Dublin Offices, providing CFD consultancy services for a wide variety of industrial applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TotalSim LLC is building a suite of web applications for industrial computational fluid dynamics (CFD) simulations. We are looking for an intellectually curious and motivated student to join our development team as a client side engineering intern. In this role, you will be responsible for the design and development of a family of reusable interface components that will be used to construct bespoke web applications for our clients. US citizenship or permanent residency required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Applicant should have:
- Front end experience (JavaScript, jQuery, Client-side frameworks)
- Linux experience
- Familiarity with version control (preferably git)
- Undergrad Sophomore, Junior, and Senior applicants accepted as well as Grad Students
Term Available: Any Semester / Flexible&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Send resume to 

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:totalsim.us*jobs?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
totalsim.us||jobs
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>