<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/tags/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:12:02 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/tags/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>CFD_Hardware</title>
      <link>http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:12:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Hardware/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware:5a023ba5d369891166b1ded5f7752210&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to software, TotalSim also provides custom high-performance computing (HPC) systems. Systems can be configured for any size or capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently building up to 32 node, 192 core clusters featuring E5-1650v2 Intel Xeon速 6 core processors. These Linux based clusters use only one system hard drive on the head node with the other nodes booting in a diskless fashion. Typically we build the clusters with QDR InfiBand速 interconnects. These systems are based on reliable Supermicro速 1U chassis and motherboards so fit nicely in standard 42U data center racks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have access to other partners that can supply a range of machine to fit your particular needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remote-computing:5a023ba5d369891166b1ded5f7752210&#34;&gt;Remote Computing:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TotalSim have vast experience in using remote HPC and can offer ways of accessing remote HPC and clouds computing centers for you peak volume&amp;hellip; contact us for details&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently we have an inventory of 2-3 year old 12 node, 48 core &amp;ldquo;single&amp;rdquo; or 24 node, 96 core &amp;ldquo;double&amp;rdquo; clusters featuring Intel速 Core i7 Quad core processors. The clusters are housed in beautifully fabricated stainless steel cabinets, custom designed by TotalSim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical 50M cell vehicle models can be meshed and solved in under 12hrs using just 48cores on one of these commodity based clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though not the latest and greatest hardware, these are very useful and affordable CFD machines&amp;hellip; we are still using them daily!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us for pricing (we&amp;rsquo;ll make a good deal on these i7 machines!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>