<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 15:04:10 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>consulting</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/consulting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 May 2015 15:04:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/consulting/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;total-sim-offers-consulting-training-support-and-development:a25d6bd4dcb7d62219c6846057abf7cb&#34;&gt;Total Sim offers Consulting, Training, Support and Development.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want consulting &amp;amp; design?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We do it every day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to create your own CFD Department?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We can guide you as a trusted partner.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are affordable for organizations of all sizes and business models because we focus on the use and development of Open Source software and utilize the best in commodity-based compute power to set up, solve, and support your solution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;design:a25d6bd4dcb7d62219c6846057abf7cb&#34;&gt;Design&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Sim applies fluid dynamic analysis to increase product performance.
Quick results take your design from idea to high performance reality in short time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;optimization:a25d6bd4dcb7d62219c6846057abf7cb&#34;&gt;Optimization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Design of Experiments, Mesh morphing, and Response Surface methods allows us to deliver optimized results and robust designs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sculptor™ Software allows us to manipulate designs in a parametric manner for infinite geometrical changes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customized Design of Experiments and Response Surface methods allow us to deliver a full map of the design space from a minimum number of runs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;flow-visualization:a25d6bd4dcb7d62219c6846057abf7cb&#34;&gt;Flow Visualization&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Expertise in visualization methods allows us to provide understanding of the complete flow field of your design so we can identify areas for improvement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We run your design, observe the flow, obtain baseline data, and then provide you understanding of the results, and areas for potentially improved solutions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;mapping:a25d6bd4dcb7d62219c6846057abf7cb&#34;&gt;Mapping&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Performance Mapping means you see your product performance results under a variety of conditions, then improvements can be made and compromises understood.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Total Sim can tell you how changes in one area of your design impacts performance in another area.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fully mapped design space means we can deliver true optimums.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;scale-able:a25d6bd4dcb7d62219c6846057abf7cb&#34;&gt;Scale-able&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Full-scale design testing is done in a real-world environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Models are tested at full-size, on the open road, without the cost of building full-scale models - saving time and money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bring us your concept and we can talk style, shape, and real world performance with you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sectors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/Sectors/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:12:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/Sectors/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFD_Hardware</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Hardware/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:12:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Hardware/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hardware:5a023ba5d369891166b1ded5f7752210&#34;&gt;Hardware&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to software, TotalSim also provides custom high-performance computing (HPC) systems. Systems can be configured for any size or capacity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are currently building up to 32 node, 192 core clusters featuring E5-1650v2 Intel Xeon® 6 core processors. These Linux based clusters use only one system hard drive on the head node with the other nodes booting in a diskless fashion. Typically we build the clusters with QDR InfiBand® interconnects. These systems are based on reliable Supermicro® 1U chassis and motherboards so fit nicely in standard 42U data center racks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also have access to other partners that can supply a range of machine to fit your particular needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;remote-computing:5a023ba5d369891166b1ded5f7752210&#34;&gt;Remote Computing:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TotalSim have vast experience in using remote HPC and can offer ways of accessing remote HPC and clouds computing centers for you peak volume&amp;hellip; contact us for details&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently we have an inventory of 2-3 year old 12 node, 48 core &amp;ldquo;single&amp;rdquo; or 24 node, 96 core &amp;ldquo;double&amp;rdquo; clusters featuring Intel® Core i7 Quad core processors. The clusters are housed in beautifully fabricated stainless steel cabinets, custom designed by TotalSim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Typical 50M cell vehicle models can be meshed and solved in under 12hrs using just 48cores on one of these commodity based clusters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though not the latest and greatest hardware, these are very useful and affordable CFD machines&amp;hellip; we are still using them daily!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact us for pricing (we&amp;rsquo;ll make a good deal on these i7 machines!)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFD_Software</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:11:51 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Software/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:gmail.com*pgruenbacher?subject=this%20is%20a%20subject%20line&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
gmail.com||pgruenbacher
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CFD_Support</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Support/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:11:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/totalsimPublic/services/CFD_Support/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>