<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on My New Hugo Site</title>
    <link>http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on My New Hugo Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:10:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/about/company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2015 11:10:57 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/about/company/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We are Total Sim&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) design team, we take innovative design ideas from initial concept to high-performance reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We stand for innovation with more than 100 years of combined design experience. We are industry-impacting with design teams in Dublin, Ohio, and Brackley, England who serve organizations of all sizes, budgets, and timetables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We deliver innovative consulting, development, training, installation and support using leading-edge OPEN and commercial tools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;team:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Team&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ray-leto:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Ray Leto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;President, Total Sim LLC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray Leto, a 25+ year veteran of open wheel racing, received a BS in Aerospace Engineering from Penn State in 1985 and began his career by working his way up through the motorsports ranks as a mechanic and engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray joined Truesports Company Racing in 1988 as an Engineer and in 1991&amp;amp; 92 worked with winning racer Scott Pruett. As a key member of Team Rahal, Leto spent 15 years honing his craft working under the direction of team owner Bobby Rahal. Ray worked within the Rahal organization in many roles including Race Engineer, Aerodynamicist, Chief Race Engineer, Technical Director, CART Team Manager, and Acting General Manager.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray helped guide Bryan Herta to his first two career CART series wins, and while managing the CART operations at Team Rahal, Ray helped Jimmy Vasser win in Fontana in 2002, and notched several CART victories, and poles with Michel Jourdain in 2003. Switching to the IRL in 2004, Ray returned his focus to aerodynamics and simulation helping the team achieve multiple wins and poles including the 2004 Indy 500 with Buddy Rice. Ray then managed the race engineering and strategy for the 2005 Indy and IndyCar Series Rookie of the Year Danica Patrick during her break-out seasons in 2005 and 2006.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ray brings more than 20 years of high pressure racing experience to his role as president of Total Sim LLC, based in Dublin, Ohio. He continues innovation and leadership as an accomplished Engineer and Manager lending his extensive aerodynamic experience, a strong focus on simulation, systems integration, and program implementation to clients in motorsports and other fields where rapid change is essential.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;naethan-eagles:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Naethan Eagles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technical Director, Total Sim LLC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naethan graduated in 1993 with an honors degree in Aeronautical Engineering from City University London. He joined a small R&amp;amp;D company that same year which provided experimental and CFD consulting services to the HVAC industry. He moved to Rolls-Royce PLC in early 1997 working on the development of the Trent series of gas turbine engines, using a combination of CFD and FEA technologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late 1998, Naethan joined Rob Lewis at Advantage-CFD initially to work with BAR F1 on their aero development program. Together Naethan and Rob went on to spearhead the aero consulting arm of ACFD, working on projects as diverse as Champ Car and Indy Racing aero development, all the way to alternative power generation systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naethan left ACFD in the summer of 2001 to start the CFD Department at the BMW-Williams F1 Team. Over the next ten years he grew the size and scope of the department, integrating the use of CFD into the aerodynamic design process, placing CFD at the heart of all aero development, and making CFD the primary tool for all conceptual aero work, cooling studies, and structural load determination. Naethan became a key part of the small team at Williams that set the design and development direction for all their projects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naethan has extensive experience in full-scale wind tunnel and track testing, including instrumentation, data capturing, and data reduction. His experience of successfully taking designs from concept through CFD and model scale wind tunnel testing, to implementation and verification on the actual vehicle gives him a rare combination of advanced modeling skills and practical understanding of racecar development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naethan decide to leave Williams F1 in 2010 to join TotalSim so he can transfer what he&amp;rsquo;s learned during his time at the &amp;lsquo;bleeding edge&amp;rsquo; of motorsports and design and bring it to bear on new areas and project types. As of January 2011 Naethan has become a fulltime member of the TotalSim USA team and will be a great resource and asset not only for TotalSim, but all of our customers as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rob-lewis:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Rob Lewis&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Board Member, Total Sim LLC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing Director, TotalSim Ltd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rob Lewis graduated with a degree in Mechanical Engineering from Leeds University in 1991 and winning a PhD scholarship to stay at Leeds and study CFD codes for combustion. After being awarded his PhD in 1994, Rob joined FLUENT Europe where he managed a team of support and consulting engineers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In late 1997, Rob left FLUENT to start AdvantageCFD (A-CFD) with Adrian Reynard at Reynard Motorsports. A-CFD supported all of Reynard Motorsports designs from Champ Car to the BAR F1 cars. Rob grew the A-CFD organization to 25 people by late 2006 when it was an essential part of Honda F1 Aerodynamics Dept. AdvantageCFD succeeded in setting the standard in motorsport CFD from inception to its closure in 2007, including Rob’s pioneering use of OpenFOAM. The switch in focus away from any outside consulting by the Honda F1 Racing Team gave Rob and some of the team at A-CFD the chance to continue working with their clients by creating a new company, TotalSim Ltd, which they formed as a largely employee owned company in early 2007.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, Rob is Managing Director of TotalSim Ltd. which employs 16 staff in Brackley, UK with over 1000 cores of compute resource. TotalSim Ltd. has become the worldwide leader in the use of OpenFOAM for Motorsports and Automotive CFD and continues to grow and expand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having worked together while at A-CFD and Team Rahal respectivly, Rob and Ray began discussions in 2007 on the idea of forming a US version of TotalSim to service key clients, and expand the use of OpenFOAM in the USA. In early 2009, Total Sim LLC started as a joint venture between TotalSim Ltd and the employees of this new company based in the US. Rob and TotalSim Ltd are also expanding into Italy via a new partnership with Y-Com forming Y-Sim in mid-2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sergio-rinland:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Sergio Rinland&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Advisor and Past Board Member, Total Sim LLC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Board Member, TotalSim Ltd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Engineering Director for Epsilon Euskadi, Azkoitia, Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sergio Rinland is an immensely respected designer and leader with an exceptional record of achievement in the competitive field of Formula One and Sports Car racing, having acted as Design Engineer, Chief Designer and Technical Director.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sergio received his Engineering degree and began his racing career in his native Argentina. Moving to the UK and Europe in the early 1980’s, Segio worked his way up in Formula One as a Designer and Race Engineer, eventually becoming Chief Designer for some of the top teams in F1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the past 4 years Sergio lead the engineering team at Epsilon in Spain including working with and instructing at the University there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since early 2011 Sergio has refocused his efforts on his consulting company Astauto Ltd. that he established in 1991. Astauto services provided covered a wide range of disciplines from the design and development of complete cars and components to aerodynamic, vehicle dynamics, and structural analysis to development of existing vehicles using the latest technologies and simulation methods. Astauto is also heavily involved in Alternative Energy developments, Electric and Hybrid Cars projects for Racing and Automotive applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sergio also holds an MBA from Kingston University, UK, and his insight into both the design and business worlds are invaluable to TotalSim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ted-pandaleon:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Ted Pandaleon&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CFD Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ted Pandaleon earned a BS with Honors in Mechanical Engineering from Lehigh University in 2007. Ted went on to receive a MSc with Distinction in Race Car Aerodynamics from the University of Southampton, in the United Kingdom. He has the distinction of being one of the only US citizens to have been awarded this MSc from Southampton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in school Ted held a wide variety of co-op and intern positions, ranging from working with a Heavy Equipment Manufacture to working for an IndyCar team. Ted&amp;rsquo;s MSc emphasis on, and personal interest in Automotive / Race Car Aerodynamics makes him a perfect fit for TotalSim&amp;rsquo;s core customer base.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;greg-padgett:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Greg Padgett&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CFD Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Greg Padgett joined TotalSim in July 2011 after completing his BS in Aerospace Engineering at The Ohio State University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During his time at OSU Greg worked as a Research Associate at the OSU Aero-Astro Research Lab on several projects related to jet engines. As well Greg worked on the Buckeye Bullet Team and participated in year long Sponsored Capstone project centered on reducing drag on road going automobiles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Greg has only been with us a short time he&amp;rsquo;s already become our go-to ANSA pre-processing expert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;mark-swift:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Mark Swift&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CFD Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Swift joined TotalSim in April 2012 after completing his BS in Aerospace Engineering at the University of Minnesota.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During his time at Minnesota Mark worked as a Research Associate at the Organelle Research Group on Microfluidics. As well Mark worked as a software development engineer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with his aerodyamnics and fluids work with TotalSim, Mark has, in his first year with us, become one of our best Python, database, and interface programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;andy-luo:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Andy Luo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CFD Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy Luo, based in southern California, joined TotalSim in November 2012 after six years at Swift Engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Andy received both his BSc and Msc from USC and has extensive experience in aerospace work including 2D and 3D airfoil and aircraft design using CFD, Wind Tunnel, and flight testing. As well, during his time at Swift Andy work on automotive and race car work. Andy was responsible for some really cool CFD work showing a race car during an active passing maneuver - all done in CFD. He is also an wiz at creating pre-processing and post processing tools using simple software interfaces like Excel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are really excited to have Andy on-board focusing on the aerospace industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;miguel-class:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Miguel Class&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CFD Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Miguel has joined TotalSim in Sept of 2013 after receiving his BS in Aerospace Engineering from OSU. Miguel had focused on some interesting projects in scholl inclusing land mine detection and design of a motor glider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At TotalSim, Miguel has focused on geometry prep, OpenFOAM case building and has turned into one of the go-to engineers we have for industrial and specialty problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ryan-winfree:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;Ryan Winfree&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CFD Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan has joined TotalSim as an intern for the summer of 2013 while he worked on his MS in Aerospace Engineering at The Ohio State University. Ryan received his BS in 2012 from OSU.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan then joined TotalSim fulltime in Jan of 2014. Prior to TotalSim he was an Undergrad Research Associate at the Aero-Astro Research Lab at OSU working mostly in the GE Engine test cell facility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ryan is focused on geometry prep and learning OpenFOAM during his internship and now full time he&amp;rsquo;s managing full CFD project from geometry prep, thru solving and post-processing. Ryan&amp;rsquo;s also been applying his scripting an programming skill to our process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;david-hesse:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;David Hesse&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Senior Research Engineer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;David Hesse, a 30 year veteran of Battelle Memorial Institute in Columbus, OH, joined TotalSim as our Senior Research Engineer in July of 2014.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a principal research scientist at Battelle, David has performed many CFD analyses for a wide range of clients in the Department of Defense, Department of Energy, numerous commercial ventures including the petroleum industry, chemical process industries, biomedical industry, and toxicological testing. He has applied commercial CFD packages, public domain codes, as well as written his own codes for special project needs. David was also involved in the space shuttle program, probabilistic fracture mechanics, electro-hydrodynamic applications, nuclear processes, X-ray lithography, mathematics for data mining, chemical micro-reactor design, biofilm modeling, atmospheric transport, and 3D printing among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are really excited to have David on-board as we expand our reach into process engineering and broader industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;avatar left&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://pgruenbacher.github.io/totalsimPublic/images/placeholder.png&#34;/&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;bb3:6987eea426d745ed1851414822c2c6fd&#34;&gt;BB3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;

&lt;a 
class=&#34;reflectable&#34; 
href=&#34;mailto:free.com*spam?subject=&amp;body=&#34;&gt;
free.com||spam
&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CFD Engineering Intern&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For several Years TotalSim has employed a graduate student working on the Ohio State Buckeye Bullet Team The team operates out of the Center for Automotive Research at OSU with the student serving as it&amp;rsquo;s new Aerodynamics Team Leader. Cary Bork and Casie Clark are the two most recent interns from this program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both have now graduted with MS&amp;rsquo;s in Aerospace - Cary working in WA for Boeing and Casie for Lockheed in GA.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the internships, the students used the resources, methods, and optimization techniques at TotalSim to help finalize the design the next generation Buckeye Bullet, the BB2.5 and now the BB3 which aims to eclipse their record at over 400mph. TotalSim is proud to help the Buckeye Bullet program and to have had these students as part of our team.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>